http://www.raeng.org.uk/terms-and-conditions/cookies

Cookies
This page describes how our web site uses cookies to improve the visitor experience and how you can manage which cookies are placed on your computer.
Cookies Policy
The Royal Academy of Engineering understands that your privacy is important to you and that you care about how your personal data is used. We respect and value the privacy of everyone who visits our website, and will only collect and use personal data in ways that are described in our Privacy Notices, and in a way that is consistent with our obligations and your rights under the law.
Cookies are small text files stored on your computing device when you visit Our Site and may be used to enable websites to run more effectively or to identify your device when you return to a website.
Our Site uses cookies to make it easier to use, to support the provision of relevant information and functionality to you, as well as to provide us with information about how Our Site is used. The type of cookies we currently use on Our Site is set out below. Certain cookies can be set as soon as you visit Our Site.
Before Cookies are placed on your computer or device, you will be shown a pop-up requesting your consent to set those Cookies. By giving your consent to the placing of Cookies you are enabling us to provide the best possible experience and service to you. You may, if you wish, deny consent to the placing of Cookies; however certain features of Our Site may not function fully or as intended
You can choose to manage the cookies we use on Our Site through your browser settings at any time. Preventing cookies is likely to affect our ability to update this Site to cater for user preferences and improve its performance.
The information below distinguishes between "first-party and third-party cookies". Whether a cookie is first or third party refers to the domain placing the cookie. First-party cookies are those used by this Site. Third-party cookies that are set by a domain other than this Site. If you visit this Site and another entity sets a cookie through it, this would be a third-party cookie.
Cookie Category
Details
Strictly necessary
These cookies will be essential first-party session cookies, and if persistent or third party, there should be a good justification for this. Not all first-party session cookies will fall into the ‘strictly necessary’ category for the purposes of the legislation. Strictly necessary cookies will generally be used to store a unique identifier to manage and identify the user as unique to other users currently viewing the website, to provide a consistent and accurate service to the user.
Our Site uses strictly necessary cookies to:
Remember previous actions (e.g. user entered text) when navigating back to a page in the same session
Load balancing session cookies for the duration of a session. Third-party social plug-in content sharing cookies (for members of a social network who have already logged in) which do not track users.
Performance
Performance cookies allow us to update this Site to cater for Site user preferences and improve performance. They collect information about how our Site is used (for example, which pages users visit most often and where error messages are delivered). These cookies don't collect information that identifies individuals. All information is aggregated and therefore anonymous.
Our Site uses performance cookies to:
Provide statistics on how this Site is used (including selections that you have made and services that you have viewed, during your use of this Site)
Gather non-user specific technical data regarding usage of this Site and provide statistics on how our Site is used
Help us improve this Site by measuring any errors that occur
Test different designs of our Site
We use Google Analytics for these purposes (please see below for further information).
Functional
Functional cookies allow our Site to remember choices you make, and any customisations you make to Site pages during your visit. They are necessary to provide features and services specific to individual users.
Our Sites uses functional cookies to:
Remember that you have been provided with our cookie information and consent notification
Fulfil a request by a user, such as using social media to share content on this Site
Remember the selected country/location and language.
Targeting
Targeting cookies are used to deliver adverts more relevant to user interests. These cookies are usually third-party cookies.
Our Site uses targeting cookies:
To collect browsing habits to target relevant adverts to the users on other websites. This is called remarketing
In conjunction with a service implemented by the Site to increase functionality, such as adding a site to the user’s social network and providing maps.
Cookies type
Design
Persistent
Persistent cookies remain on a device for the period specified in the cookie. They are activated each time the user visits the website that created that particular cookie.
Session
Session cookies contain information that is stored in a temporary memory location and then subsequently deleted after the session is completed or the web browser is closed. This cookie stores information that the user has inputted and tracks the movements of the user within the website. A session cookie is also known as transient cookie.
What are the specific cookies used on Our Site?
Cookie name
Purpose
Category
First party or third party cookie?
Session or persistent?
ASP.NET_SessionId
It’s a temporary cookie which assigns an identification number to each visitor so that they can navigate the site correctly.
Strictly necessary
First
Session
.ASPROLES
It recognises registered users and allows them to access their account preferences
Strictly necessary
First
Session
.ASPXFORMSAUTH
It is used to authenticate users when login to Academy’s web site.
Strictly necessary
First
Session
Cookie Acceptance Site cookie
This cookie is set to help us remember that you have seen the cookie message required by law and accepted it.
Strictly necessary
First
Persistent
Cookie Acceptance Site Consent cookies
analytics, socialsharing
It will place a cookie to remember your consent for the category such as “analytics” or “social sharing”. If “analytics” settings are accepted, it will allow the google analytics cookies to store and vice versa If “social sharing” settings are accepted, it will allow them to store cookies for social sharing & vice versa. This cookie will be removed when the user revokes consent to that category.
Functional
First
Persistent
CMSPreferredCulture
Records your preferred language and regional settings.
Functional
First
Persistent
Google Analytics
_utma, _utma, _utmb,_utmc,
_utmz,_utmv
Are used to generate statistics about visitors to the website to help improve the website. It collects information in anonymous form.
Performance
First
Persistent
CMS CurrentContact
This cookie helps us understand how visitors use our web site.
Performance
First
Persistent
__stid
is a random unique identifier not tied to any personally identifiable information (PII), and is used to associated users with topics of interest, based upon the content they consume and share.
Targeting
Third
Persistent
_uset
indicate when a user has been cookied so that we don't repeat the task in the next 8 hours
Targeting
Third
Persistent
ShareThis.com Twitter cookies
twitter_sess, Perzonalization_id, guest_id, ct0
Used for Twitter sharing buttons.
Targeting
Third
Persistent
ShareThis.com Facebook
datr, lsd, reg_fb_gate, reg_fb_ref, reg_ext_ref, wd, _e_3bXO_0
Used for Facebook
Targeting
Third
Persistent
Doubleclick.net cookies
DSID, IDE
These are publicity cookies, used to improve publicity.
Targeting
Third
Persistent
For further information about Google Analytics, visit:
https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/
https://developers.google.com/analytics/resources/concepts/gaConceptsCookies
Social media website cookies
Users can ‘like’ or share our content on the likes of Facebook and Twitter where we have included sharing buttons on Our Site.
The privacy implications for this will vary from social media network to social network media and will be dependent on the privacy settings you have chosen on these networks.
Cookies policy does not cover third party websites
Please note that this Cookies Policy does not apply to, and we are not responsible for, the privacy practices of third party websites which may be linked or accessed through Our Site.
Changes to this Cookies Policy
We may change this Cookies Notice and we would encourage you to review the policy from time to time to stay informed of how we are using cookies. This Cookies Policy was last updated May 2018.
Terms and conditions
Disclaimer
Cookies
Privacy policy
